export const CHEMISTRYA2012 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A solution whose concentration is known is a",
A: "concentrated solution.",
B: "dilute concentration.",
C: "saturated solution.",
D: "standard solution.",
answer: "D. standard solution.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following radioactive nuclides W, X, Y and Z with half-lives 5.73 x 103 years, 2.91 x 102 seconds, 3.00 x 105 years and 1.38 x 102 days respectively, is most stable?",
A: "W",
B: "X",
C: "Y",
D: "Z",
answer: "C. Y",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. How many electrons are there in 2713Al3+?",
A: "10",
B: "13",
C: "14",
D: "16",
answer: "A. 10",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The electron configuration of copper is [Ar] 3d104s1 and not [Ar] 3d94s2 because of",
A: "extra stability of the filled d-orbital.",
B: "unstable nature of the s-orbital.",
C: "low energy of the d-orbital.",
D: "high energy of the d-orbital.",
answer: "A. extra stability of the filled d-orbital.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of A. Y and Z the following species determines the chemical properties of an atom?",
A: "Electron",
B: "Neutron",
C: "Nucleus",
D: "Proton",
answer: "A. Electron",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following statements is not is a correct about the structure of the atom?",
A: "Electrons are arranged in shells around the nucleus.",
B: "The two electrons in the ls orbital have the same spin quantum number.",
C: "The energy of 1s electron 1s different from that of 2s.",
D: "No two electrons can have the same values for the four quantum numbers.",
answer: "B. The two electrons in the is orbital have the same spin quantum number.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following letters represents the element that is most likely to form coloured compounds?",
A: "Q",
B: "X",
C: "M",
D: "N",
answer: "B. X",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following pairs of letters represents elements that exist as diatomic gases?",
A: "Y and Z",
B: "P and Z",
C: "M and P",
D: "N and Y",
answer: "A. Y and Z",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following metals represents an alkali metal?",
A: "P",
B: "N",
C: "R",
D: "Z",
answer: "B. N",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A metalloid is represented by the letter",
A: "Q",
B: "S",
C: "Y",
D: "Z",
answer: "B. S",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. If the electron configuration of an element is 1s22s22p63s23p3 , where would the element be located on the periodic table?",
A: "Group V; period 5",
B: "Group V; period 3",
C: "Group III; period 5",
D: "Group III; period 3",
answer: "B. Group V; period 3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following electron configurations is that of a noble gas?",
A: "1s22s22p63s23p2",
B: "1s22s22p63s23p6",
C: "1s22s22p63s1",
D: "1s22s22p5",
answer: "D. 1s22s22p5",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following reactions occurs rapidly?",
A: "I2(s)+2KCl(aq)➔2KI(aq)+Cl2(l)",
B: "I2(s)+2KCl(aq)➔2KI(aq)+Br2(l)",
C: "Br2(l)+2KCl(aq)➔2KBr(aq)+Cl2(l)",
D: "Br2(l)+2KI(aq)➔2KBr(aq)+I2(l)",
answer: "D. Br2(l)+2KI(aq)➔2KBr(aq)+I2(l)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. What type of bond would be formed between two elements A and B with electron configurations: 1s22s22p63s1 and 1s22s22p5, respectively?",
A: "Covalent bond",
B: "Co-ordinate covalent bond",
C: "Metallic bond",
D: "Ionic bond",
answer: "D. Ionic bond",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following compounds is covalent?",
A: "CaCl2",
B: "HCl",
C: "KCl",
D: "MgCl2",
answer: "B. HCl",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. NH+4 is formed from NH3 and H+ by",
A: "dative bonding",
B: "ionic bonding",
C: "covalent bonding",
D: "hydrogen bonding",
answer: "A. dative bonding",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. In which of the following elements is the metallic bonding strongest?",
A: "11Na",
B: "12Mg",
C: "13Al",
D: "19K",
answer: "C. 13Al",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. What are the values of X, Y and Z respectively in the following equation? MnO2+XHCl(aq)➔YH2O(l)+ZCl2(g)",
A: "4, 1, 2",
B: "1,2,1",
C: "2, 1, 2",
D: "4,2, 1",
answer: "D. 4,2, 1",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The mass of 800 cm3 of a gas Q at s.t.p is 1.0 g. What is the molar mass of Q?  [l mole of a gas at s.t.p occupies 22.4 dm3]",
A: "18.0 g mol−1",
B: "22.4 g mol−1",
C: "28.0 g mol−1",
D: "36.0 g mol−1",
answer: "C. 28.0 gmol-1",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following substances contains the same number of particles as 10.6g of Na2CO3 [C= 12.0; O=16.0; Na=23.0]",
A: "0.01 mole of O2",
B: "0.10 mole of CaCO3",
C: "0.13 mole of NaOH",
D: "0.50 mole of CO2",
answer: "B. 0.10 mole of CaCO3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. If the molar mass of Y(HCO2)2 is 162 gmol−1 , determine the relative atomic titration of ethanoic acid against sodium hydroxide is mass of Y[H= 1.0; C= 12.0; O = 16.0]",
A: "40",
B: "48",
C: "61",
D: "101",
answer: "A. 40",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following pairs of gases produces dense white fumes when mixed?",
A: "H2S and HCl",
B: "H2S and CO2",
C: "NH3 and CO2",
D: "NH3 and HCl",
answer: "D. NH3 and HCl",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A gas that is collected by upward delivery is likely to be",
A: "soluble in water",
B: "heavier than air",
C: "insoluble in water",
D: "lighter than air",
answer: "D. lighter than air",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following substances sublimes when heated?",
A: "Sodium chloride",
B: "Calcium oxide",
C: "Ammonium chloride",
D: "Aluminium oxide",
answer: "C. Ammonium chloride",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. An example of a gas which dissolves in water to give an acidic solution is",
A: "Chlorine",
B: "Hydrogen",
C: "Nitrogen",
D: "Oxygen",
answer: "A. Chlorine",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. An aqueous solution of Na2CO3 is",
A: "alkaline",
B: "acidic",
C: "amphoteric",
D: "neutral",
answer: "A. alkaline",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The most suitable indicator for the titration of ethanoic acid against sodium hydroxide is",
A: "Iodine solution",
B: "Methyl orange",
C: "Methyl red",
D: "Phenolphthalein",
answer: "D. Phenolphthalein",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following oxides is amphoteric?",
A: "MgO",
B: "Na2O",
C: "Al2O3",
D: "CuO",
answer: "C. Al2O3",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following pairs of substances are electrolytes?",
A: "NH3(l) and HCl(aq)",
B: "NH3(g) and HCl(l)",
C: "NH3(aq) and HCl(g)",
D: "NH3(aq) and HCl(aq)",
answer: "D. NH3(aq) and HCl(aq)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The pH of a 0.0001 moldm−3 solution of hydrochloric acid is",
A: "1",
B: "2",
C: "3",
D: "4",
answer: "D. 4",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following equations represents a neutralization reaction?",
A: "BaCl2(aq)+Na2SO4(aq)➔BaSO4(ag)",
B: "CaCO3(aq)+2HCl(aq)➔CaCl2(aq)+CO(g)+H2O(l)",
C: "HNO3(aq)+NaOH(aq)➔NaNO3(ag)+H2O(l)",
D: "2H2S(g)+SO2(g)➔3S2(s)+2H2O(l)",
answer: "C. HNO3(aq)+NaOH(aq)➔NaNO3(ag)+H2O(l)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. What is the amount of hydroxide in 25 cm3 of 0.05 mol dm−3 of potassium its solution?",
A: "0.0125 moles",
B: "0.1250 moles",
C: "1.2500 moles",
D: "12.5000 moles",
answer: "A. 0.0125 moles",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A solvent is suitable for recrystallization of a salt if the solute",
A: "dissolves more readily in the hot solvent than in the cold solvent.",
B: "dissolves readily in the solvent at room temperature.",
C: "dissolves more readily in the cold solvent than in the hot solvent.",
D: "decomposes in the solvent when heated.",
answer: "A. dissolves more readily in the hot solvent than in the cold solvent.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following factors would increase the solubility of a solute in a solvent?",
A: "Stirring the mixture vigorously",
B: "Increasing the temperature of the mixture",
C: "Increasing the surface area of the solute",
D: "Increasing the pressure of the mixture",
answer: "B. Increasing the temperature of the mixture",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following conditions would increase the yield of NH3?",
A: "Addition of iron catalyst.",
B: "Increase in the temperature of the system",
C: "Increase in the volume occupied by reactants",
D: "Increase in the total pressure of the system",
answer: "D. Increase in the total pressure of the system",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following statements about a chemical system in equilibrium is correct?",
A: "The reaction is irreversible",
B: "The reaction goes to completion",
C: "The equilibrium position is affected by catalyst",
D: "The equilibrium is re-established when a stress is applied",
answer: "D. The equilibrium is re-established when a stress is applied",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Redox reaction is a process in which there is",
A: "loss and gain of electrons by the relevant species.",
B: "removal of oxygen and addition of hydrogen.",
C: "no change in oxidation numbers of the relevant species.",
D: "addition of oxygen and removal of hydrogen.",
answer: "A. loss and gain of electrons by the relevant species.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. What is the function of manganese (IV) oxide in the reaction represented by MnO2+HCl➔MnCl2 ?",
A: "Dehydrating agent",
B: "Oxidizing agent",
C: "Reducing agent",
D: "Catalyst",
answer: "B. Oxidizing agent",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. What is the oxidation number of sulphur in Fe2(SO4)3?",
A: "+2",
B: "+3",
C: "+4",
D: "+6",
answer: "D. +6",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. What is the basicity of the compound with the following structure?",
A: "4",
B: "3",
C: "2",
D: "1",
answer: "C. 2",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following pairs of compounds would react to produce CH3COOCH3",
A: "HCOOH and CH3CH2OH",
B: "CH3COOH and CH3OH",
C: "CH3COOH and (CH3)2CHOH",
D: "C2H5OH and CH3COOH",
answer: "B. CH3COOH and CH3OH",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following methods could be used for the laboratory preparation of",
A: "Heating a mixture of sodium ethanoate with soda lime",
B: "Addition of calcium carbide to water",
C: "Heating a mixture of ethanol and concentrated H2SO4",
D: "Addition of ethanoic acid to Na2CO3(aq)",
answer: "A. Heating a mixture of sodium ethanoate with soda lime",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The compound 2, 2, 4-trimethylpentane is an isomer of",
A: "pentane.",
B: "propane.",
C: "heptane.",
D: "octane.",
answer: "D. octane.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Saponification is a chemical process which can be referred to as",
A: "decomposition.",
B: "hydrolysis.",
C: "neutralization.",
D: "oxidation.",
answer: "B. hydrolysis.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. What product is formed when acidified potassium tetraoxomanganate(VII) is added to ethane under mild condition?",
A: "CH2OHCH2OH",
B: "CH3CH2OH",
C: "CH3CH3",
D: "CH3COOH",
answer: "A. CH2OHCH2OH",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Two isomers that can be represented by the molecular formula C12H22O11",
A: "sucrose and lactose.",
B: "maltose and galactose.",
C: "sucrose and fructose",
D: "glucose and fructose",
answer: "A. sucrose and lactose.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following carbohydrates is a polysaccharide?",
A: "Cellulose",
B: "Fructose",
C: "Glucose",
D: "Sucrose",
answer: "A. Cellulose",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following substances is a condensation polymer?",
A: "Rubber",
B: "Nylon",
C: "Polyethene",
D: "Polyvinyl chloride",
answer: "B. Nylon",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Global warming is likely to cause",
A: "increased humidity",
B: "water pollution",
C: "rise in sea level",
D: "air pollution",
answer: "C. rise in sea level",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following gases is used in the treatment of water for domestic use?",
A: "O2",
B: "Cl2",
C: "Br2",
D: "SO2",
answer: "B. Cl2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]